Guide to the Hartbeat magazine collection ARCH166
University of Hartford Archives & Special Collections
Hartbeat magazine collection
2007 - 2017
University of Hartford Archives & Special Collections
ARCH166
0.44 Linear Feet (2 containers)
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open to all researchers. There are restricted files within the collection in accordance to the archives restriction policy concerning FERPA protected records.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of records pertaining to the creation of Hartbeat magazine as well as copies of the magazine from 2011 - 2017.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into two series: I. Founding records and II. Hartbeat Magazines.
Existence and Location of Copies
Scanned or digital versions of some issues of Hartbeat can be accessed at: http://mdid3.hartford.edu. Access to the digital repository is limited to the University of Hartford Campus.
Periodicals; College student newspapers and periodicals; Student publications; University of Hartford
- Founding records, 2007 - 2012, undated
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains records, plans, and correspondence regarding the creation Hartbeat and its inaugural issue.
  Arrangement
  Files in this series are arranged in rough chronological order.
  - Hartbeat Data Analysis, 2007 - 2010 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Research on Job Titles, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Documents From Meetings, 2009 - 2010 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Emails, 2010 - 2011 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Restricted in accordance to archives restriction policy regarding FERPA protected records.
  - Hartbeat Magazine Advertisements, 2010; 2 Files (2 oversized folders) (Box Shared Small Oversized 1)
  - Development of Hartbeat, 2011 Jul 07 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Emails Between Hartbeat and Inside, 2011 Sep 13 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Hartbeat Printing Order, 2011 Sep 19 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Printing Estimates, 2011 Sep 21 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Template Magazine, 2011 Sep (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Release Party, 2011 Oct 22 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Unotes Article, 2011 Oct 25 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Hartbeat Magazine [Proof] Issues, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Hartbeat Conditions, 2011 - 2012 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Informer Acquires Hartbeat, 2012 Apr 1 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Contains a clipping from the April Fool's issue of the Informer about the student newspaper acquiring Hartbeat magazine.
  - Hartbeat Logo Design, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Hartbeat Photographer/Writer Ads, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Staffing Responsibilities, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Student Government Association, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Hartbeat Magazines, 2011 - 2017
  - 2011 Fall (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - 2012 Spring (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - 2012 Fall (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - 2013 Spring
    PUBLISHER'S NOTES, by Thompson Mhlanga, pg.3; NINE DAYS BAND, by Thompson Mhlanga, pg. 4; KNOWLEDGE OF SELF, by Ghazi Shbazz Omair, pg. 8; HAWKS HELPING HARTFORD, by Terence Dily Jr., pg. 10; TALENT SHOW RECAP, by Thompson Mhlanga, pg. 14; HAWKS FROM AROUND THE WORLD, pg. 16; BSU'S FASHION SHOW, by Angela Francisco, pg. 18; PRESIDENT OBAMA'S VISIT, Jessica Drury, pg. 26; MARIA ARROYO, by Terence Dildy Jr., pg. 28; AJA WILSON, by Thompson Mhlanga, pg. 30; ACE OF DIAMONDS, by Terence Dildy Jr., pg. 34; POETRY, by Terrence Dildy Jr., pg. 36; IS THERE GOD ON CAMPUS?, by SANDI SMITH, pg. 37; MEET THE TEAM, pg. 40; CUT ABOVE PERSONALITY (PHOTO CONTEST WINNERS), pg. 46.
  - 2014 Spring (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - 2014 Fall (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - 2015 Spring
    THE OBOIST WITH A PLAN, by Desiree Roberts, pg. 4; LIFE AFTER COLLEGE: GRADUATING SENIORS, by Eboni Rhodes, pg. 7; The Life of an Educator, by Carolyn Johnson, pg. 12; BUILDING A LEGACY...DEFINING ARCHITECTURE, by Shanetta Murray, pg. 14; MADE IN AMERICA: BSU FASHION SHOW, Desiree Roberts, pg. 20; 31, by Rob Dozier, pg. 24; HAWKS DRIVE FOR EAGLES, by Simani Natta, pg. 26; 30th Annual International Festival, by Carline Desir, pg. 30; THE ISSUE ON RACE, by Rob Dozier, pg. 36.
  - 2015 Fall (Box 1, Folder 23)
    Marriage Equality in America: What's Next?, Desirée Roberts; Devoted To Students: Profile of Dr. Bharat Kolluri, Cori Ansbro; University of Hartford Athletics is Turning Over a New Leaf, Simani Natta; The American Dream is Real, Bryson Owens; We Do Matter, Masai Kofa-Wilson; Entertaining for the Past Seven Years and Counting: Dramatis Personae, Desirée Roberts; "Style is a way to say who you are without having to speak," Samantha Spector; Soil Holds Secrets to Resolve Antibiotic Resistance, Katelyn Whitburn; Teaching through Connection: Profile of Dr. Ann Costello, Cori Ansbro; Whistle Blower Hotline, Livia McHugh.
  - 2016 Spring (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - 2016 Fall
    Black in America, Breyonna Henderson; A Summer in Brazil, Jessica Floyd; Get To Know Your Student Government Assocation, Jessica Floyd; Club Spotlight: W.A.R.S. – Making a Difference, Cori Ansbro; To You, Marzjani James-Henderson; Relationships, Bo-Edward Lawrence; Club Spotlight: UHA Steppaz, Staff; Ballin 4 Ever, Bryson Owens; Uplifting Women One Day at A Time: Professor Lisa Cato-Scott, Shanice Johnson; Revolution of Love, Paolo Celentano; FORTY Years of Desmond, Bryson Owens; Her Thoughts, Marzjani James-Henderson.
  - 2017 Spring (Box 1, Folder 25)
    Spotlight: Sue Fitzgerald, by Bryson Owens, p.4; Women With a Purpose: Walk a Mile in Her Shoes, by Jessica Floyd, p.6; Farewell Walt, by Bryson Owens, p.11; Poetry Corner: Window Frame, by Bo Edward Lawrence, p.16; Sigma Alpha Pi: Bringing Leadership and Success to Students, by Corrine Ansbro, p.17; No Small Alumna: Monique Smalls, by Jessica Floyd, p.19; Poetry Corner, Distance, by Bo Edward Lawrence, p.21; BSU Fashion Show 2017, by Staff, p.23; Alternative Spring Break (ASB) Community Service: Center for Community Service, by Staff, p.31; The Family of the Hour: The Obama's, by Niecey Johnson, p.37; University of Hartford Welcomes Next President: Gregory Woodward, by Corinne Ansbro, p.41.